DAN KLEIN: One thing that we often do
is we draw the graph associated with
the problem.
And this is helpful in a lot of ways.
So for the case of a binary constraint
satisfaction problem where each
constraint connects at most
two variables, right?
We could have a constraint on
just a single variable.
It would be called a
unitary constraint.
This might be the graph for
the Australia case.
So in a binary constraint graph,
the nodes are the variables.
So you can see here, essentially
it mimics the structure of
the Australia graph.
And arcs indicate the presence
of a constraint.
Notice that they don't say
what the constraint is.
In particular, the constraint here
between WA and NT was an inequality
constraint.
But the graph doesn't show that.
It just shows that there
is a constraint.
Why do we want graphs like this if
they don't actually encode which
constraint is there?
And that's because a lot of general
purpose algorithms will use the graph
structure to speed things up.
For example, we could recognize that
Tasmania is disconnected from the
graph, and solve it independently,
which is really easy.
We'll see other algorithms next
lecture that also exploit the
structure of the constraint
graph to speed things up.
Let's take a look at N Queens.
So here is the five Queens problem.
Drawn gloriously by myself.
So here's five Queens.
A, B, C, D, and E are the rows.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5 are the columns.
And now drawn in this wonderful
applet by AI Space is the
variables in circles.
And you can see their
domains below them.
And every one of these
arcs is a constraint.
So for example, A and B, the
first two rows have some
constraint between them.
And in this particular output,
it's called Queens 1.
What the heck is the Queens
1 constraint?
Well, it says things like they can't
both be 1, and they can't be A is 1,
and B is 2, and so on.
That's all living inside this constraint
here called Queens 1.
OK, we'll come back to this.